Partial Register of the Bulgarian subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Bulgarian Subject Collection
1913-2016
86089
Hoover Institution Archives
54 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 3 videotape cassettes (25.2 linear feet)
Pamphlets, serial issues, newsletters, election campaign literature, press summaries, and video tapes, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Bulgaria; Bulgarian history from the mid-nineteenth century through World War II; allegations of Bulgarian involvement in the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II in 1981; and post-1990 elections in Bulgaria.
Access
Collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, serial issues, newsletters, election campaign literature, press summaries, and video tapes, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Bulgaria; Bulgarian history from the mid-nineteenth century through World War II; allegations of Bulgarian involvement in the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II in 1981; and post-1990 elections in Bulgaria.
John Paul II, Pope, 1920-2005.; Bulgaria--History.; Bulgaria--Politics and government--1944-1990.; Bulgaria--Politics and government--1990-.; Bulgaria.; Elections--Bulgaria.; Video tapes.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1878-1993 (Box 1-6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Pamphlets, bulletins, election campaign material, press articles, press digests, official government publications, pictorial charts, and miscellany printed matterial, arranged chronologically and then alphabetically by subject
  - Reprints of documents relating to various 19th century events, Bulgarian workers movement and social-democratic parties, uprisings and World War II partisan movement, put out by the Bulgarian Communist Party, 1971-1981. In Bulgarian, 1878-1944. (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and printed miscellany relating to post-World War II Bulgarian politics, the situation of Turkish and Macedonian minorities, the Orthodox Church, and to allegations of Bulgarian involvement in the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II in 1981. Includes pictorial chart of government members in 1985, and speeches of Todor Zhivkov. In Bulgarian and English, 1944-1990.
  - 1990-
    - Economy. Statistical surveys, bulletins, and official government releases, 1991-1992
    - Elections, Pamphlets, bulletins, leaflets, and other printed matter, relating to elections in Bulgaria and political conditions surrounding them. In Bulgarian and English, 1991-1992.
      - General
      - Political parties (Box 2)
        - List of contents. Detailed lists of election material organized by party
        - Alternativna Sotsialliberalna Partiia
        - Alternativno Sotsialistichesko Obedinienie
          - Bulgarska Demokraticheska Partiia
        - Bulgarska Demokratichna Mladezh
        - Bulgarska Komunisticheska Partiia
        - Bulgarska Natsionalno Demokraticheska Partiia
        - Bulgarska Rabotichesko Selska Partiia
        - Bulgarska Raboticheskaia
          - Sotsialdemokraticheskaia Partiia
        - Bulgarska Sotsialdemokraticheskaia Partiia
        - Bulgarska Sotsialisticheska Partiia (Box 3)
        - Bulgarska Sotsialisticheska Partiia
          - Parliamentaren Soyuz za Sotsialna
          - Demokratsia
        - Bulgarski Biznes Blok
        - Bulgarski Demokratichen Tsenter
        - Bulgarski Konstitutsionen Forum
        - Bulgarski Natsionalen Soyuz
        - Bulgarski Orel
        - Bulgarski Soyuz za Evropeiskaia Federatsiia
        - Bulgarski Zemedelski Naroden Soyuz
        - Demokraticheska Partiia. Konservativen Sgovor
        - Demokratichno Dvizheniie za Konstitutsionna
          - Monarkhia
        - Dvizheniie za Demokratsiia i Sotsialna
          - Spraviedlivost
        - Dvizheniie za Prava i Svobody
        - Ekoglasnost
        - Federatsiiata na Anarkistite v Bulgaria
        - Glavno Myuitiystvo na Myuslyumanite v
          - Republika Bulgariia
        - Konservativna Partiia (Box 4)
        - Konstitutsionen Soyuz
        - Kristian Demokraticheski Soyuz
        - Kristian Republikanska Partiia
        - Kristiansko Zhensko Dvizhenie
        - Liberalen Kongres
        - Liberalno Demokraticheska Partiia
        - Monarchist Conservation Union of Bulgaria
        - Natsionalen Patriotichen Soyuz
        - Nezavisima Demokratichna Partiia
        - Otechestvenata Partiia na Truda
        - Parlamenteren Soyuz za Sotsialna Demokratsia
        - Parlamentarna Grupa na Dvizhenieto za Prava
          - i Svobodi
        - Partiia Liberali
        - Partiia na Sobstvenitsite v Bulgariia
        - Radikaldemokraticheskata Partiia v Bulgariia
        - Republikanska Partiia v Bulgarii
        - Rusenski Soyuz Tsarstvo Bulgariia
        - Sotsialisticheskii Soyuz Molodezhi
        - Soyuz na Demokratichnite Sily
        - Zelena Partiia
    - Government (Box 5)
      - General. "Express Media Bulletin", weekly press digest relating to various aspects of Bulgarian society, In English, July-December, 1991.
      - Council of Ministers. Official government bulletins, December 1992
      - Directory of governmental agencies. "BTA Spravochnik Bulgaria", 1992
      - Minister of Defense, Dimitr Ludzhev. Speech and miscellany (Box 6)
      - Parliament. Press bulletin
      - President, Zhelyu Zhelev. Speeches, press articles, government bulletins
        - General
        - Election campaign, 1991
        - Vice-President, Blaga Dimitrova
    - Political conditions
      - General
      - Autonomy of academic institutions
      - Royal family. Miscellany depicting Tsar Simeon II and family
      - Trade union movement
- PERIODICALS, 1990-1993. (Box 7-9)
  Serial issues relating to political conditions in Bulgaria, arranged alphabetically by title. In Bulgarian
  - Bulgaria, Sofia, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Bulgarski Fermer, Sofia, 1990
  - Bulgarski Glas, Sofia, 1990
  - Demokratichna Sedmitza, Sofia, 1990
  - Detektiv I66, Sofia, 1990
  - Dialog, Sofia, 1990
  - Dien, Sofia, 1990
  - Ekoglasnost, Sofia, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Ekopolitika, Sofia, 1990
  - Evropa, Sofia, 1990
  - Fakt, Sofia, 1990
  - Impuls, Sofia, 1990
  - Khristian Demokratzia, Sofia, 1990
  - Komunistichesko Delo, Sofia, 1990, 1991
  - Kurier, Sofia, 1990
  - Misl, Sofia, 1990
  - Mladezh, Sofia, 1990
  - Mladezhko Zemedelsko Zname, Sofia, 1990
  - Muslumanlar, Sofia, 1990
  - Nachalo, Sofia, 1990, 1991
  - Nie, Vidin, 1990
  - Nov Dien, Sofia, 1990
  - Nova Era, Sofia, 1990
  - Nova Svetlina, Sofia, 1990
  - Pari, Sofia, 1991, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Patriot, Sofia, 1990
  - Ploshad Demokratzia, Sofia, 1990
  - Pogled, Sofia, 1993
  - Politika, Sofia, 1990, 1991
  - Praven Nabljudatel, Sofia, 1992
  - Proslava, Sofia, 1990
  - Protest, Sofia, 1990
  - Puls, Sofia, 1990
  - Rabotnik, Sofia, 1992
  - Reforma, Sofia, 1990
  - Republika, Sofia, 1990
  - Rikoshet, Sofia, 1992
  - Rodopski Ustrem, Sofia, 1990
  - Smiakh, Sofia, 1991
  - Sofiisko Utro, Sofia, 1990
  - Svoboda, Plovdiv, 1990
  - Svremenen Pokazatel, Sofia, 1990
  - Tempo, Sofia, 1990
  - Transporten Glas, Sofia, 1990
  - Vecherni Noviny, Sofia, 1990
  - Vek 21, Sofia, 1990
  - Zemedelska Borba, Sofia, 1991
  - Zora, Sofia, 1990, 1992, 1993
- MEMORABILIA, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Political party pins and election tote bag (Box 6)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1992. (Tape cabinet Tape cabinet)
  - 1 videotape relating to Alexander Nevsky Cathedral (Tape cabinet Tape cabinet)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 10-58)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu